# **Doug Melvin**

Engineering manager and experienced agilist, passionate about working with stakeholders to deliver what they need, when they need it, and working with engineering teams to ensure psychological safety and that they have all the resources they need to deliver their best work.

☑ dmelvin122@gmail.com 📞 (646) 246-4953 👽 Denver, CO in https://www.linkedin.com/in/douglasmelvin/

### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Charter Communications**

Senior Manager, Data Platforms

September, 2022 - Present

- I make certain my team's workload and priorities are appropriately distributed, and that the team has a full understanding of the business and architecture vision
- I act as the representative for the product vision when working with my team, and I advocate for the best
  engineering solution when working with the product team, always striving to accomplish what product needs
  in line with engineering best practices and the recommendations of my principal, lead, and senior engineer

Lead Software Delivery Manager

November, 2021 - September, 2022

 I converted from contractor to full time in 2021, continuing my existing role, after working with Charter as a contractor starting in the fall of 2013

# **Kenzan (Now Sourced Group, An Amdocs Company)**

Senior Agile Solutions Professional

May, 2015 - November, 2021

As a Senior ASP, I acted as the scrum master, project and program manager, agile coach, and business analyst
for my team to manage our planning through the product and software life cycles from new project setup
through deployment and production operations support

Project Manager/Business Analyst

May, 2013 - May, 2015

• I maintained development roadmaps, release plans, and sprint plans down to the epic and story level, ensuring that my team remained on time, on spec, and on budget while maximizing value to our clients

#### PROJECT

#### **Content Management System**

2013-Present

 In my tenure with Charter, I have spent the majority of my time working on the content management system serving our customer portals and MySpectrum app, providing all of the support content, banners, and vanity URLs, among other content

Push Notifications 2020-Present

 My team owns the platform we use to ingest data from across the company and send push notifications to customer devices on our MySpectrum app

# Certifications

- PMI Professional in Business Analysis (PMI-PBA) #2997940
- PMI Agile Certified Practitioner (PMI-ACP) #1774872

# SKILLS

Engineering Management, Client Relations, SAFe, Teamwork, Problem Solving, Atlassian Suite Administration

# EDUCATION

# The George Washington University

Computer Science June 2013

Theta Tau, Professional Engineering Fraternity